♪ Here we are going far ♪
♪ to save all that we love ♪
♪ If we give all we’ve got ♪
♪ we will make it through ♪
♪ Here we are like a star ♪
♪ shining bright
on your world today ♪
♪ Make evil go away ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we’ll
withstand it all ♪
♪ Code Lyoko be there
when you call ♪
♪ Code Lyoko we
will stand real tall ♪
♪ Code Lyoko
stronger after all ♪
Dear students,
this magnificent stadium
is being built in close cooperation
with the board of education.
Soon, you will be enjoying
the latest in sports equipment,
and I personally am delighted
since my duty is to provide you
with the finest working conditions
possible, and in all areas.
Both intellectual and athletic.
Since, as Juvenal said,
“A sound mind in a sound body.”
Wow, can he talk.
Do we really have to
listen to all this?
Not really.
You could’ve stayed
with Jeremie if you wanted to.
What’s Einstein up to, anyway?
The usual.
He’s glued to
his computer screen
in a big cyber-conversation
with his darling Aelita.
Just a couple of
calculations to go,
and my devirtualization program
will be completed.
And…do you really think
it’s going to work, Jeremie?
Do I have a chance of finally
becoming materialized in your world,
and becoming somebody…
somebody like you?
I sure hope so.
Anyway, there’s one thing
that I’m sure of.
I’ve never been as close
to the answer as I am now.
Honestly, it’s so hard to imagine.
We can be face to face
in the same room.
We can touch each other.
Even kiss.
Uh, yeah.
That’d be uh…interesting.
I mean, well uh, I guess.
Now, get ready.
I’m starting the test program.
I don’t get it.
It’s not the end of the world.
I’m sure, Jeremie,
that one day you’ll succeed.
Aelita, I…
I’m beginning to wonder
if I’m up to the job.
If I’m good enough for
such a complicated program.
I’m sorry. I’m just
tired and jumpy, that’s all.
I’d better go and stretch my legs.
See you later.
Huh? Jeremie?
Hey, what’s this?
Another one of Jeremie’s
materialization programs.
Oh, wow! Candy!
Odd!
How many times
have I told you
not to touch my computer
when I’m not here?
There are months of work in there!
Relax, Max!
I didn’t hurt your little toy.
Oh, no.
You’re such a cosmic creep.
Now look what you’ve done.
Those keys are incredibly sensitive.
Okay, okay.
A little piece of candy’s
not gonna wreck your keyboard!
Huh?
That’s crazy!
This is really mega insane!
Yes, it works!
Odd, you’re a genius,
you know that!
Hey, make up your mind!
Am I a genius or a creep?
You’re a creepy genius.
You didn’t do it on purpose,
but by dropping the candies
on the keyboard,
you modified and
relaunched my program!
I don’t know exactly
what happened, but it works!
Thanks, Odd!
Who’s an Einstein now?
Are you gonna materialize Aelita?
Well, yeah.
The problem is I only get
one try and that’s it.
That’s because I didn’t see
what kind of programming
the candy typed in.
Yeah, so?
There’s only one Aelita.
Go and tell the others.
I’ll announce
the good news to Aelita.
Yumi, it’s now or never.
We may not get a second chance.
What if there’s some kind of bug?
I’ll never be able to
set up the program again!
Listen, you can’t just
materialize Aelita like that
without making a lot of preparations.
I’ve boosted the scans.
I’ve got the program going.
Everything’s ready.
Yeah, in your head.
Hey, come back to earth, Jeremie.
Try to be practical for once.
Aelita has no parents,
and she hasn’t got
a birth certificate.
What’s more, she’s not
enrolled in any school.
Okay, that’s no biggie,
but all that together means
she doesn’t exist in our world.
Imagine,
“Hello, I’m Aelita,
“I just got here
from a virtual reality!”
That’s a one-way ticket
to the nuthouse.
You know, Jeremie,
it doesn’t have to be today.
I can wait.
Well, what do we do now?
I can put her up at my house.
My folks wouldn’t mind.
And you could plug into
the city hall computers,
and create a phony
identity for her.
Find her a new name.
All the stuff she needs.
Then you just have to
enroll her at our school.
And try to put her in our class!
That’d be really cool, huh?
Okay.
We’ll get started
first thing tomorrow.
Aelita, are you asleep?
Am I asleep?
Come on, Jeremie, you know that
virtual beings never sleep.
I can’t sleep a wink.
I can’t stop thinking
about your materialization,
and it's keeping me up.
You can’t imagine all the things
you’re gonna discover in our world.
You mean like sleeping?
That’s right.
That and all kinds of fun things.
Tell me more.
(SNORING)
(SINISTER MUSIC)
When you touch an object
with your fingers,
you have a sort of sensation.
It could be a feeling
of softness or of heat.
It could be cold.
Oh, I see.
I thought you only sensed
with your brain.
That’s right.
But it’s a little more complicated.
Here on earth,
everyone has five senses.
You, Aelita,
you only have two of them.
Hearing and seeing.
You can only see and hear.
Speaking of hearing…
Soon you’re gonna be
able to touch, and to…
Jeremie, I think I just heard XANA.
He’s up to something.
What’s all the noise about, I wonder.
Jeremie, XANA’s launched an attack.
Okay. Listen, Aelita.
Go and hide in a deactivated tower.
I’ll contact you from the factory.
Odd, wake up!
XANA’s attacking!
What was that?
W-What did you say
about carpet tacking?
Ulrich, get up!
It’s a XANA alert!
What did you say?
I said it’s a XANA alert!
XANA’s attacking!
Hey, do you always sleep
with those things in your ears?
Yeah, Odd. Always.
And one of these days,
I’ll tell you why.
No need to look any further, guys.
This time he picked a real winner.
He’s attacking us with bulldozers!
Nice going, XANA.
How subtle can you get?
Jeremie, rush over
to the lab and call Yumi.
Odd and I are gonna
try and stop these monsters.
I’ll take the front one.
Got you.
(CELL PHONE RINGS)
Come on, Yumi, get up!
We really need you!
Do you realize what time it is?
Bulldozers? What bulldozers?
What!?
Hey, XANA’s controlling the thing!
I don’t know what to do, Ulrich!
That makes two of us.
You go and meet
Yumi and Jeremie at the lab.
If I can find out what XANA
wants to do with these monsters,
that sure would help.
Okay. Just be careful.
Keep your eyes open, Aelita.
You never know where
XANA’s monsters are hiding.
Don’t worry, Jeremie.
No enemy in sight for the moment.
But the pulse beats
are getting stronger.
The activated tower
can’t be too far away.
Aelita, don’t worry.
Odd should be there soon.
And now let’s hope that
Yumi and Ulrich are on their way.
Ulrich?
He’s on the bulldozer
trying to find out what XANA’s up to.
Ulrich, do you read me?
Bad news, Jeremie.
I’m on the river bank.
And I’m afraid XANA’s
targeted the factory.
That’s got to be it.
If XANA manages
to destroy our factory,
we can say goodbye
to our equipment.
No more computer meaning
no more communication with Aelita.
Don’t forget about the scans.
Without them,
no more transfers to Lyoko.
And that means
total victory for XANA.
Ulrich, listen.
Odd’s just about to go it alone,
so if you don’t mind, hurry up.
I’ll do my best,
but I can’t promise you
a graceful entrance.
Transfer Odd.
Scanner.
Virtualization.
Oh, hello, Odd.
You’re looking stressed.
No, I’m okay, Aelita.
It’s just that I never know
what I’m gonna find
whenever I come here.
Come with me, Odd.
The activated tower is this way.
Okay. Let’s go and check it out.
Oh, no!
Ulrich, do you read me?
Jeremie?
Yumi, I’ve lost contact with Ulrich.
Where was he
when you last spoke to him?
He was heading
for the factory with the bulldozers.
Right. I’m almost there.
I’ll find him.
That way.
Talk about a reception committee.
Usually roachsters
move in groups of five.
Wow, and it looks like
the committee's a full strength.
Hello, roachsters.
Now, which one of you
wants to be first?
Hey, would you cool it,
huh, Odd?
Your mission is to
protect Aelita, remember?
You want to trade places, Jeremie?
Ulrich!
Ulrich, get up! Ulrich, hurry up!
Odd, you’ve used up
four of your ten arrows.
Here comes three more.
Laser arrow!
Ulrich, you’ve got to get up!
Ulrich!
Hey, Jeremie,
can you give me a hand?
What about the bulldozers?
It’s a mess up there.
I wish it were only up there.
How’s Odd doing?
Jeremie, I’m starting to get
a little lonely out here!
That answer your question?
Gotcha.
Okay, Odd.
Yumi’s on her way.
As for Ulrich, let’s just say
he’s fast asleep.
He is? Well, that must be tough.
I mean, without his ear plugs.
Transfer Yumi.
Scanner.
Virtualization.
Odd, figure out a way
to slow down the roachsters.
You’re way ahead of Yumi.
Take care of the tower.
I’ll take care of the roachsters.
Let’s see what the score is.
Three roachsters
and three laser arrows left.
Odd, this is no time
to miss your target.
Jeremie, how many
life points have I got left?
Ten. Hang on.
Yumi’s almost there.
(WHISTLES)
That’s it for you.
Where’s your buddy hiding?
Yumi--
uh-oh.
No!
Hey, Jeremie,
I didn’t make it in time.
It’s game over for Odd.
I’ll back up Aelita
in case she needs help.
I don’t want to
stress you out or anything,
but if the scans are destroyed,
you’re on a one-way trip, Yumi.
No problem. I’ll hurry.
I wouldn’t mind
a little nap before class.
Jeremie, it isn’t the scanner
she has to worry about.
I just had a vision.
I saw Yumi falling
into the digital void.
Virtualized forever?
Hey, Yumi.
I head him.
I’ll go and help her.
What?
Come on, Ulrich,
take a look at yourself.
The shape you’re in, it’d be crazy.
Odd, help me.
Jeremie.
I saw it.
Yumi’s on her way to help you.
Give me a visual.
There it is!
That’s exactly
where I saw Yumi fall!
Transfer Ulrich.
Scanner.
Virtualization.
Jeremie, I can’t hold on anymore.
Aelita’s inside the tower now.
Hang on, Yumi.
I can’t…
Yumi, I coming!
Yumi!
No!
(INAUDIBLE)
I never would’ve
thought it was possible
for one of us to become…
It’s all my fault.
If I had been faster,
she would still be here.
But there is a solution.
And Jeremie knows what it is.
The materialization program.
It’s operational, but Aelita has to
give up her place to Yumi.
Can you bring Yumi back here?
Yes, but I can only
materialize one person.
One and only one.
Then choose Yumi.
She’s part of your world already.
It’s okay.
I can wait a little longer.
Okay, Aelita.
But first of all, I need to
track down Yumi in the digital void.
It’s alright, Yumi,
you’re gonna be okay.
Welcome home!
But…
how did you
get me back here?
I’m happy,
and at the same time, I’m sad.
Why?
At least you know
the program works!
You just have to
set it back up again.
Yeah, nothing to it.
I have faith in you, Jeremie.
One day, you’ll get me there.
I’m sure.
Hey, Jeremie,
want some candy?
Hey, what are you
doing with that? It’s mine!
Oh, yeah, I guess it is.
Okay, no problemo.
Here you go.
Come on, have one.
Candy can fix anything.
Even a broken heart.
If you say so.
CLOSED CAPTIONING PROVIDED BY
REDDIT.COM/R/CODELYOKO